culturesforhealth.com 2017-12-20

# Cultures for Health Privacy Policy | Customer Privacy

This Application collects some Personal Data from its Users. Your privacy is important to us. We will not share your information with any third party except as required by law or as necessary to complete an order placed by you with us and conduct normal business operations (see below). Please feel free to call or email us with any questions regarding our privacy policy.

Cultures for Health  
200 Innovation Ave. Ste. 150  
Morrisville, NC 27560  
customersupport@culturesforhealth.com

**  
Types of Data Collected**

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookie, Usage Data, Email, First Name, Last Name and Phone Number.

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection. 

The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application. 

Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by the Application or by the owners of third-party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User. 

Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.

The User assumes responsibility for the Personal Data of third parties published or shared through this Application and declares to have the right to communicate or broadcast them, thus relieving the Data Controller of all responsibility.

**Method of Processing**

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification or unauthorized destruction of the Data. 

Access to the Data may be available to Data Processors such as employees involved with the processing or to external parties providing services to the Data Controller, third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communication agencies. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

**Place**

The Data is processed at the Data Controller headquarters, unless stated otherwise in the rest of this document.

**Conservation Time**

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request the Data Controller for their suspension or removal.

**The Use of the Collected Data**

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Application to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: advertising, remarketing and behavioral targeting, interaction with external social networks and platforms, RSS feed management, analytics, managing email addresses and sending messages, contacting the User, handling payments, displaying content from external platforms, managing support and contact requests, and interaction with support and feedback platforms.

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

### Advertising

These services allow User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this Application, possibly based on User interests. 

This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below. 

Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e., displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Application. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

**AddShoppers**

AddShoppers is an onsite marketing platform provided by Add Shoppers, LLC. 

Personal data collected: Email, Name, Cookie 

Place of Processing: USA - [Privacy Policy](http://www.addshoppers.com/privacy)

#### Google AdSense (Google)

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of this Application and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered. 

Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: [google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en).

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://google.com/privacy/ads/)

#### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. 

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

### Contacting the User

#### Mailing List or Newsletter (This Application)

By registering to the mailing list or to the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Application. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Application or after performing a purchase.

Personal data collected: Email, First Name and Last Name.

#### Contact Form (This Application)

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the Users authorizes this Application to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal data collected: Email, First Name, Last Name, and Phone Number.

#### Phone Contact (This Application)

Users that provided their phone number might be contacted for commercial or promotional purposes related to this Application, as well as for fulfilling support requests.

Personal data collected: Phone number.

### Displaying content from external platforms

These services allow you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them.  
If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.

#### Youtube Video (Google)

Youtube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

### Handling Payments

Payment processing services enable this Application to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Application shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.

#### Paypal (Paypal)

Paypal is a payment service provided by Paypal Inc., which allows users to make online payments using their Paypal credentials.

Personal data collected: Various types of Data.

### Interaction with External Social Networks and Platforms

These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application.  
The interaction and information obtained by this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Facebook Like Button and Social Widgets (Facebook)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

#### Google+ +1 Button and Social Widgets (Google)

The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### Pinterest “Pin it” Button and Social Widgets (Pinterest)

The Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Pinterest platform provided by Pinterest Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://about.pinterest.com/privacy/)

#### Twitter Tweet Button and Social Widgets (Twitter)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy)

### Managing Support and Contact Requests

These services allow this Application to manage support and contact requests received via email or by other means, such as the contact form. 

The Personal Data processed depend on the information provided by the User in the messages and the means used for communication (e.g., email address).

#### Email Center Pro

Email Center Pro is a support and contact request management service provided by Palo Alto Software, Inc.

Personal data collected: Various types of Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.emailcenterpro.com/privacy.php "Email Center Pro Privacy Policy")

### Managing Email Addresses and Sending Messages

These services make it possible to manage a database of email contacts to communicate with the User via email. 

The services are used to collect data concerning the date and time when the mail is viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacts with incoming mail, such as by clicking on links included in the email.

**AddShoppers**

AddShoppers is an onsite marketing platform provided by Add Shoppers, LLC. 

Personal data collected: Email, Name, Cookie 

Place of Processing: USA - [Privacy Policy](http://www.addshoppers.com/privacy)

#### Listrak

Listrak is an email address management and message sending service provided by Listrak, Inc.

Personal data collected: Email.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.listrak.com/Privacy.aspx "Listrak Privacy Policy")

### RSS Feed Management

These services allow this Application to manage RSS feeds and the distribution of their content. Depending on the characteristics of the service used, these services may be used to insert ads within the content and to gather statistics data from them.

#### Feedburner (Google)

Feedburner is a service to manage RSS feeds provided by Google Inc. It allows the collection of statistics on what content is consulted and to insert ads in it.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

### Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting

These services allow this Application and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User. 

This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.

**AddShoppers**

AddShoppers is an onsite marketing platform provided by Add Shoppers, LLC. 

Personal data collected: Email, Name, Cookie 

Place of Processing: USA - [Privacy Policy](http://www.addshoppers.com/privacy)

#### Listrak

Listrak is an email address management and message sending service provided by Listrak, Inc.

Personal data collected: Email.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.listrak.com/Privacy.aspx "Listrak Privacy Policy")

#### AdWords Remarketing (Google)

AdWords Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Adwords advertising network, the Doubleclick Cookie and in some cases the [http://www.teracent.com/about-us/privacy-policy/](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/222678/Taracent%20Cookie). 

For the opt-out: [http://google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/222678/google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en) and [http://www.teracent.com/about-us/opt-out/](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/222678/www.teracent.com/about-us/opt-out/).

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### Google Analytics for Display Advertisers (Google)

Google Analytics for Display Advertisers is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie. 

For the opt-out: [http://google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/222678/google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en).

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

## Granify Behavioral Targeting

Granify collects and processes information in order to personalize the Cultures for Health site for users and enhance user experience through the provision of Granified Prompts.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

### Legal Action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services.

### Additional Information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data.

### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

### Information Not Contained in this Policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time at its contact information.

### The Rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request the Data Controller to erase the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.

### Information about this Privacy Policy

Cultures for Health is responsible for this privacy policy.
